export default {
  id: 'low_1006_2_2a',
  name: '상용한자(2학년-2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '売(賣)', answer: ['팔 매', 'う(る)、う(れる)', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '買', answer: ['살 매', 'か(う)', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '門', answer: ['문 문', 'かど', 'もん'] },
    { question: '戸(戶)', answer: ['집 호', 'と', 'こ'] },
    { question: '行', answer: ['다닐 행', 'い(く)、ゆ(く)、おこな(う)', 'こう、ぎょう、あん'] },
    { question: '来(來)', answer: ['올 래', 'く(る)、きた(る)、きた(す)', 'らい'] },
    { question: '歩(步)', answer: ['걸음 보', 'ある(く)、あゆ(む)', 'ほ、ぶ、ふ'] },
    { question: '走', answer: ['달릴 주', 'はし(る)', 'そう'] },
    { question: '止', answer: ['그칠 지', 'と(まる)、と(める)', 'し'] },
    { question: '方', answer: ['모 방', 'かた', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '角', answer: ['뿔 각', 'かど、つの', 'かく'] },
    { question: '市', answer: ['저자 시', 'いち', 'し'] },
    { question: '場', answer: ['마당 장', 'ば', 'じょう'] },
    { question: '心', answer: ['마음 심', 'こころ', 'しん'] },
    { question: '体', answer: ['몸 체', 'からだ', 'たい、てい'] },
    { question: '頭', answer: ['머리 두', 'あたま、かしら', 'とう、ず、と'] },
    { question: '首', answer: ['머리 수', 'くび', 'しゅ'] },
    { question: '顔', answer: ['얼굴 안', 'かお', 'がん'] },
    { question: '色', answer: ['빛 색', 'いろ', 'しょく、しき'] },
    { question: '羽', answer: ['깃 우', 'は、はね、わ', 'う'] },
    { question: '毛', answer: ['털 모', 'け', 'もう'] },
    { question: '丸', answer: ['둥글 환', 'まる、まる(い)、まる(める)', 'がん'] },
    { question: '形', answer: ['모양 형', 'かた、かたち', 'けい、ぎょう'] },
    { question: '刀', answer: ['칼 도', 'かたな', 'とう'] },
    { question: '店', answer: ['가게 점', 'みせ', 'てん'] },
    { question: '長', answer: ['길 장', 'なが(い)', 'ちょう'] },
    { question: '用', answer: ['쓸 용', 'もち(いる)', 'よう'] },
    { question: '才', answer: ['재주 재', '재주', 'さい'] },
    { question: '科', answer: ['과목 과', '과목', 'か'] },
    { question: '答', answer: ['대답할 답', 'こた(える)、こた(え)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '引', answer: ['끌 인', 'ひ(く)、ひ(ける)', 'いん'] },
    { question: '線', answer: ['줄 선', '줄', 'せん'] },
    { question: '弓', answer: ['활 궁', 'ゆみ', 'きゅう'] },
    { question: '矢', answer: ['화살 시', 'や', 'し'] },
    { question: '汽', answer: ['물 끓는 김 기', '물 끓는 김', 'き'] },
    { question: '船(船)', answer: ['배 선', 'ふね、ふな', 'せん'] },
    { question: '台(臺)', answer: ['토대 대/별 태', '토대/별', 'だい、たい'] },
    { question: '光', answer: ['빛 광', 'ひか(る)、ひかり', 'こう'] },
    { question: '紙', answer: ['종이 지', 'かみ', 'し'] },
    { question: '午', answer: ['낮 오', '낮', 'ご'] },
    { question: '元', answer: ['으뜸 원', 'もと', 'げん、がん'] },
    { question: '広(廣)', answer: ['넓을 광', 'ひろ(い)、ひろ(まる)、ひろ(める)、ひろ(がる)、ひろ(げる)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '太', answer: ['클 태', 'ふと(い)、ふと(る)', 'た、たい'] },
    { question: '池', answer: ['못 지', 'いけ', 'ち'] },
    { question: '谷', answer: ['골짜기 곡', 'たに', 'こく'] },
    { question: '岩(巖)', answer: ['바위 암', 'いわ', 'がん'] },
    { question: '星', answer: ['별 성', 'ほし', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '風', answer: ['바람 풍', 'かぜ、かざ', 'ふう、ふ'] },
    { question: '海(海)', answer: ['바다 해', 'うみ', 'かい'] },
    { question: '高', answer: ['높을 고', 'たか(い)、たか、たか(まる)、たか(める)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '原', answer: ['근원 원', 'はら', 'げん'] },
    { question: '雪', answer: ['눈 설', 'ゆき', 'せつ'] },
    { question: '野', answer: ['들 야', 'の', 'や'] },
    { question: '黄(黃)', answer: ['누를 황', 'き、こ', 'おう、こう'] },
    { question: '黒(黑)', answer: ['검을 흑', 'くろ、くろ(い)', 'こく'] },
    { question: '雲', answer: ['구름 운', 'くも', 'うん'] },
    { question: '地', answer: ['땅 지', '땅', 'ち、じ'] },
    { question: '図(圖)', answer: ['그림 도', 'はか(る)', 'ず、と'] },
    { question: '電', answer: ['번개 전', '번개', 'でん'] },
    { question: '話', answer: ['말씀 화', 'はな(す)、はなし', 'わ'] },
    { question: '国(國)', answer: ['나라 국', 'くに', 'こく'] },
    { question: '家', answer: ['집 가', 'いえ、や', 'か、け'] },
    { question: '思', answer: ['생각 사', 'おも(う)', 'し'] },
    { question: '考', answer: ['생각할 고', 'かんが(える)', 'こう'] },
    { question: '活', answer: ['살 활', '살', 'かつ'] },
    { question: '切', answer: ['끊을 절/모두 체', 'き(る)、き(れる)', 'せつ、さい'] },
    { question: '合', answer: ['합할 합', 'あ(う)、あ(わす)、あ(わせる)', 'ごう、がっ、かっ'] },
    { question: '同', answer: ['한가지 동', 'おな(じ)', 'どう'] },
    { question: '回', answer: ['돌아올 회', 'まわ(る)、まわ(す)', 'かい、え'] },
    { question: '帰(歸)', answer: ['돌아갈 귀', 'かえ(る)、かえ(す)', 'き'] },
    { question: '何', answer: ['어찌 하', 'なに、なん', 'か'] },
    { question: '明', answer: ['밝을 명', 'あ(かり)、あか(るい)、あか(るむ)、あか(らむ)、あか(らか)、あ(ける)、あ(く)、あ(くる)、あ(かす)', 'めい、みょう'] },
    { question: '当(當)', answer: ['마땅할 당', 'あ(たる)、あ(てる)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '直', answer: ['곧을 직', 'ただ(ちに)、なお(す)、なお(る)', 'ちょく、じき'] },
    { question: '間', answer: ['사이 간', 'あいだ、ま', 'かん、けん'] },
    { question: '理', answer: ['다스릴 리', '다스릴', 'り'] },
    { question: '通(通)', answer: ['통할 통', 'とお(る)、とお(す)、かよ(う)', 'つう、つ'] },
    { question: '知', answer: ['알 지', 'し(る)', 'ち'] },
    { question: '晴(晴)', answer: ['맑을 청', 'は(れる)、は(らす)', 'せい'] },
    { question: '細', answer: ['가늘 세', 'ほそ(い)、ほそ(る)、こま(か)、こま(かい)', 'さい'] }
  ]
}
